Alfred I. Hallowell Papers 1892-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.26
American Philosophical Society
- Series V - Research Files, 1892-1964 (Box 22-38)
  - Sex Ratio, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Social Learning, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Southeast (Box 37)
  - Southwest, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Spatial Orientation, 3 folders (Box 37)
    - Folder 1, 1936-1953 (Box 37)
    - Folder 2, 1905-1949 (Box 37)
    - Folder 3, n.d. (Box 37)
  - Spinning and Weaving (Box 38)
  - Student Papers, n.d. (Box 38)
  - Thematic Apperception Test, 1943 (Box 38)
  - Thematic Apperception Test--Micronesia, n.d. (Box 38)
  - [Unity of the Human Mind], [1930s-1960s] (Box 38)
  - Urmonotheisms, 1930-1933, n.d. (Box 38)
  - War, n.d. (Box 38)
  - MISC.
    - A.I. Hallowell Bookplates
- Series VI - Photographs
  Contains photograph albums, loose prints and negatives taken by Hallowell or others, or given to him during the course of his career. This series also contains reproduction photographs and copy negatives (total 27 boxes) made for research purposes, along with photocopies of most of the reproduction photographs and log sheets. A description of each reproduced item is included in the appendix as well as a detailed narrative of the photograph conservation project.
  Researchers seeking to view images from Subseries A-F are requested to use the reproduction photographs.
  Organization of reproduction photographs to be used for research use:
  The photographs and negatives that pertain to Hallowell's research on Native Americans in the United States and Canada were chosen for reproduction (Subseries A-F). Postcards were not reproduced. Each unique image in Subseries A-F has a research photograph and a copy negative. The research photographs have been reprinted from the original negative when possible.
  The photographs have been organized to follow the order of the original photograph albums as closely as possible, with the exception of Subseries F. Basic arrangement for Subseries A-E is from left to right and/or top to bottom, depending on the photograph's original placement on the page. Subseries F, which consists of loose prints never included in an album, has been grouped by approximate geographic location or subject matter as described in the description of each reproduced item.
  The reproduction photos are housed individually in polyethylene sleeves along with a stabilizing acid-free board. A label affixed to each board gives the unique number of the image, the tribe or group, location, names of people, dates, cross references to other similar images, and any other information that can be found on or with the photograph or supplied by outside researchers.
  Hallowell's personal comments, sometimes written on the verso of prints or on envelopes containing images, are the primary source for identification. Comments provided by other sources are enclosed within brackets, and when available, the outside sources have been noted. The amount of information provided varies. For instance, in Subseries A, many times a group picture has only one person identified, and thus that name is the only one on the label. In contrast, most of the individuals in Subseries E are identified.
  All the photographs are considered to be taken by Hallowell unless otherwise noted. Some photographs in Subseries A were taken by Steve Boggs. The photographs in Subseries D may have been given to Hallowell by Frank Gouldsmith Speck.
  Native American Images Note: Over 1,500 black & white silver gelatin photographs of Ojibwa, Abenaki, and Mohegan tribes of Manitoba, Ontario, and Quebec. Taken by Hallowell from ca.1920-1940 to support his ethnological research, the images are primarily portraits of individuals located outside their respective dwelling or settlement wearing some cultural accessories. Organized in subseries lettered A-J, subseries E and F illustrate artifacts such as drums, canoes, baskets, papoose and utensils. Of note are many prints of dome and pointed wigwams. Subseries I and J contain over 150 black and white postcards of Aztec, Navajo, and Hopi pottery, dwellings, and sculpture. Oversize materials include pencil sketch maps of settlements by native consultants Kiwegwan, Adam Keeper, and Neapit and ink sketch designs for birch bark scrolls by John Keeper. Each photograph has been reproduced with companion copy negatives. An itemized appendix describes each image. Some photographs are published in Hallowell’s The Ojibwa of Berens River, Manitoba (1992).
  - Subseries A. Berens River Ojibwa Album, 1930s; Copy: 338 photos
    Contains photographs of individuals, settlements, scenery, ceremonies, and Hallowell's trip "en route". Prints are arranged into locales, such as Little Grand Rapids and Pauingessi. Many of the photographs showing a group of people have only one person identified by Hallowell, and in this case, the label only names the one person. Additional photographs from this area are in Subseries F.
    Description of the reproduction photographs 7.5 boxes of photos & 1.5 boxes of negatives; 338 images.
    - Berens River, 1930 - 1933; A1
      Arriving by boat at the dock at the mouth of the Berens River.
    - Berens River, 1930 - 1933; A2
      The Wolverine and Keenora at Berens River. Hallowell first met William Berens here in July 1930.[J. Brown 2/96]
    - Berens River, 1930 - 1933; A3
      The Grand Rapids, steamship, at the dock at Berens River.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Treaty Days, 1933; A4
      Treaty at Berens River community 1930s [J. Brown 2/96] See also: A5, A6, A7, A87, A88, F87
      Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Treaty Days, 1933; A5
      Treaty at Berens River community 1930s [J. Brown 2/96] See also: A4, A6, A7, A87, A88, F87
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Treaty Days, 1933; A6
      Treaty at Berens River community 1930s [J. Brown 2/96] See also: A4, A5, A7, A87, A88, F87
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Treaty Days, 1933; A7
      Treaty at Berens River community 1930s [J. Brown 2/96] See also: A4, A5, A6, A87, A88, F87
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Chief William Berens, [ca. 1930] [1938?]; A8
      See also: A9, A10, A11, A12, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F88, F89, F92, F164, F285
      Berens, William, Chief; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Chief William Berens, [ca. 1930] [1938?]; A9
      Chief William Berens -- J. Brown 3/90 See also: A8, A10, A11, A12, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F88, F89, F92, F164, F285
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Chief William Berens, [ca. 1930] [1938?]; A10
      See also: A8, A9, A11, A12, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F88, F89, F92, F164, F285
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Chief William Berens, 1930 - 1933; A11
      See also: A8, A9, A10, A12, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F88, F89, F92, F164, F285
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Chief William Berens, 1930 - 1933; A12
      Chief William Berens with granddaughter Bertha (Everett) Flett. See also: A8, A9, A10, A11, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F88, F89, F92, F164, F285
      Berens, William, Chief; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Chief William Berens, 1930 - 1933; A13
      "En route" with moose meat- Hallowel and his party were travelling upriver on the Berens River from Berens River village to Little Grand Rapids, Manitoba. See also: A8, A9, A10, A11, A12, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F88, F89, F92, F164, F285
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Nancy Berens and grandchild, 1930 - 1933; A14
      Nancy Berens (Everett) and a grandchild in a mossbag and tikanagan. See also: A15
      Berens, Nancy, Mrs., (ne Everett); Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Nancy Berens and grandchild, 1930 - 1933; A15
      Nancy Berens (Everett) and a grandchild in a mossbag and tikanagan. See also: A14
      Berens, Nancy, Mrs., (ne Everett)
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, John Berens, 1930 - 1933; A16
      John Berens, son of Chief William Berens and Nancy Berens, with puppies. "he said that he loved those dogs more than anything. He has several storis about having to catch fish to feed the dogs. He would ice fish and catch a big pile for the dogs ('about 3,000)"-- Cathy Collins, May 14, 2012) See also A20, A18.
      Berens, John; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Chief William Berens, 1930 - 1933; A17
      See also: A8, A9, A10, A11, A12, A13, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F88, F89, F92, F164, F285
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, John Berens and Matilda Everett with snowshoes, 1930 - 1933; A18
      John Berens and Matilda Everett with snowshoes. See also A16, A20.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, young man with tame owl, 1930 - 1933; A19
      Scope and contents note
      Joe Berens, newphew of Chief William Berens, with tame owl. Adopted because his mother died of influenza in the epidemic.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, William Berens & his wife Nancy Everett with family members., 1930 - 1932; A20
      Berens Family, William Berens and his wife Nancy (Everett) and their children. Clockwise from lower left: Ida May Berens, Alice (Dolly) Berens (Everett) wtih infant, Rosie Berens (Mrs. Atoine Bittern), Percy Berens, William Berens, Jr., Mary Rose (his wife), John Berens, Bertha and Matilda Everett, Alice's daughters. See also A241, A242, A243, A244, A245.
      Berens, John; Berens, Nancy, Mrs., (ne Everett); Berens, William, Chief; Percy Berens; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Berens River, home of Chief William Berens, 1930 - 1933; A21
      The house occupied by William Berens & his family at mouth of Berens River.
    - Berens River, log building, 1930 - 1933; A22
      Log building in Berens River village
    - Berens River bay, 1930 - 1933; A23
      View of bay at the mouth of the Berens River
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, girl and puppy, 1930 - 1933 [1936?]; A24
      Scope and Content note
      girl and puppy
      Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, children, 1930 - 1933 [1936?]; A25
      Boy and girl with puppies and kitten. See also: A26
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, children, 1930 - 1933 [1936?]; A26
      Boy and girls and kitten. See also: A25
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, John Berens, 1930 - 1933 [1936?]; A27
      John Berens, son of Chief William Berens and Nancy Berens (ne Everett) riding bareback on a horse. Berens River village.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, woman and three children, 1930 - 1933 [1936?]; A28
      Alice (Dolly Berens) Everett and three children,Mathilda, Bertha, and Marie Everett, Berens River village. See also A 25, A 26.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, William Berens Jr., Mary Rose Berens and Percy Berens., 1930 - 1933 [1936?]; A29
      From left to right, Mary Rose Berens (wife of William Berens Jr.), Willam Berens Jr. (eldest son of Chief William Berens) and Percy Berens (second youngest son) untangling a fishing net. Berens River village.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River,, woman carrying pack, 1930 - 1933; A30
      Woman carrying pack. Berens River village.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, 1930 - 1933; A31
      p. 17 of Hallowell album. Same as: C7
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, 1930 - 1933; A32
      p. 17 of Hallowell album
      Same as: C2
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, two women and two children in front of Hudson Bay Company store, 1930 - 1933; A33
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, [1930 - 1933]; A34
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, 1930 - 1933; A35
      p. 19
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, 1930 - 1933; A36
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, 1930 - 1933; A37
      p. 20
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, 1930 - 1933; A38
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, [1938?]; A39
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Morning Star with two daughters, [1938?]; A40
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, [1938?]; A41
      Morning Star p. 22
      See also: F256, F257
    - Berens River, Hudson's Bay Company dog train, 1930 - 1931; A42
      Hudson Bay Company dog train. [Photographer Sgt. Putnam? -- M. Matthews 4/12]
    - Berens River, Hudson's Bay Company dog train, [1930 - 1933?]; A43
      Scope and Contents
      [Photographer Sgt. Putnam? -- M. Matthews 4/12]
    - Berens River, Hudson's Bay Company York boat, [1930 - 1933?]; A44
      Hudson Bay Company York Boat under sail on Lake Winnipeg
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, party accompanying Hallowell, 1932 or 1933; A45
      "En route -- Our party at first portage above Little Grand Rapids." Left to right 1, 2. Atoine Bitterns (son-in-law of Chief William Berens), 3. Gordon Berens (son of William Berens), 4., 5. Chief William Berens.
      Berens, Gordon; Berens, William, Chief; Bittern, Atoine; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Berens River by canoe, [1930s]; A46
      "En route -- Stop over - Island of Jack Pine"
    - Ojibwa, Berens River by canoe, [1930s]; A47
      "En route" Stopped to unload at portage.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River by canoe, [1930s]; A48
      "En route" -- Lining at rapids
    - Ojibwa, Berens River by canoe, [1930s]; A49
      1 canoe load on rocks at portage
    - Ojibwa, Berens River by canoe, [1930s]; A50
      "En route - G.R. - B.R." (Little Grand Rapids - Berens River) Canoe at rest and two men.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River by canoe, [1930s]; A51
      "En route - Pop Hill - G.R." (Poplar Hill -- Little Grand Rapids) one man carrying large pack.
    - Berens River, English Rapids, 1933; A52
      "En route - English Rapids" (Originally Sturgeon Falls was written & later crossed out).
    - Berens River, Sturgeon Falls, [1930s]; A53
      "12 miles up. Sturgeon Falls."
    - Berens River, canoe shooting rapids, [1930s]; A54
      1st rapids, canoe with motor going down the rapids. (Prior digital object graphics:6304)
    - Berens River, Wolverine Rapids, [1930s]; A55
      "En route - Wolverine Rapids."
    - Berens River, above Wolverine Rapids, [1930s]; A56
      "En route - G.R. - B.R. (Grand Rapids - Berens River) above Wolverine Rapids."
    - Berens River, below Moose Falls, [1930s]; A57
      "En route - Moose Falls." (below)
    - Berens River, above Moose Falls, [1930s]; A58
      "En route - Moose Falls" (from above).
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, steep bank stopover, [1930s]; A59
      "En route -- We stopped here to boil the kettle. Picture us clambering up this rocky slope."
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, tea break, [1930s]; A60
      "En route -- Another view taken while on our way up the river. Note the bottles-they are made of copper & heat up in no time and stay hot forever." Atione Bittern is facing the camera upper left.
      Bittern, Atoine; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Berens River rapids, [1930s]; A61
      "En route"
    - Berens River rapids, [1930s]; A62
    - Berens River rapids, old fort, [1930s]; A63
      "En route" -- Old fort
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Atoine Bittern, [1930s]; A64
      "En route -- One of the Indians with a moose head." This is Atoine Bittern, Chief William Berens' son-in-law (married to Wm's daugter Rosie) who hunted and cooked for Hallowell on his inland trips.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, tea break on rocks, [1930s]; A65
      "En route -- Going up the river we fell in with several canoes and when one stopped we all had to-no individuality up here. The chief is in the foreground. The pants and white hat over on the side is me." William Berens front right side of photo.
      Berens, Gordon; Berens, William, Chief; Hallowell, A. Irving, (Alfred Irving), 1892-1974; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Berens River rapids, 1933; A66
    - Berens River, Sharp Rock Rapids, 1933; A67
      "Sharp Rock"
    - Berens River, White Beaver Rapids, 1933; A68
      "En route -- White beaver"
    - Berens River, Crooked Falls, 1933; A69
      "En route -- Crooked Falls - Falls on the left going up"
    - Berens River, after forest fire, 1933; A70
      "After the fire"
    - Berens River rapids by canoe, [1930s]; A71
      "En route" Small canoe shooting rapids on left
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Chief William Berens, Gordon Berens and Atione Bittern, 1933; A72
      "En route". People, left to right, Atione Bittern (son-in-law of Chief William Berens, married to daughter Rosie), Gordon Berens (son of Chief William Berens, and Chief William Berens near tents.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Wolverine Rapids, [1938?]; A73
      Men (?) shooting Wolverine Rapids. [can't be seen - M.Matthews 4/12]
    - Berens River, Conjuring Falls, 1938; A74
      Conjuring Falls
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Canoe from Pauingassi, July 1938; A75
      Pauingassi [Hallowell wrote as Pauingessi] men arriving at Wolverine Rapids. [Traveling on the Berens River with canoes and a "kicker" (a small ourboard motor of 4-5 horsepower).]
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Kettle Portage, 1938; A76
      Kettle Portage
      See also: F153
    - Berens River rapids, [1930s]; A77
    - Berens River rapids, [1930s]; A78
    - Berens River, Sturgeon Falls, [1930s]; A79
      "En route -- Sturgeon Falls" (?)
    - Berens River, Moose Picture Rock, [1930s]; A80
      "En route -- Rock at Moose Picture Portage on which paintings appear"
      See also: A81, A82, F100
    - Berens River, Moose Picture Rock, [1930s]; A81
      "En route -- Moose Picture Rock"
      See also: A80, A82, F100
    - Berens River, Moose picture rock, [1930s]; A82
      See also: A80, A81, F100
    - Little Grand Rapids, approach from water, [1930s]; A83
      "Grand Rapids" [Little Grand Rapids -- J. Brown 2/96]
    - Little Grand Rapids, view from fire tower, [1930s]; A84
      "Grand Rapids"-- [Little Grand Rapids -- J Brown 2/96]. Photo taken from Fire Tower at Little Grand Rapids
    - Little Grand Rapids, float plane landing on Family Lake, [1930s]; A85
      Grand Rapids [Little Grand Rapids? -- J. Brown 2/96]. Float plane landing on Family Lake.
    - Little Grand Rapids, view of island camp, log house, [1930s]; A86
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Treaty day, [1933?]; A87
      Treaty at Little Grand Rapids.
      See also: A88,A89, F87
      Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Treaty day, [1933?]; A88
      Treaty day at Little Grand Rapids
      See also: A87, A 89, F87
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Zhaabandowaan, Keeper family, [1938?]; A89
      p. 44 of Berens River Album, Zhaaandowaan, long house, with three girls. Note stovepipe and combination of birch bark and cloth or hide coverings. Home of Kiiwiichens Keeper and his family.
      [The Keeper dwelling? Little Grand Rapids? -- J. Brown 2/96].
      See also: A91, A93, F73, F107
      Keeper, Kamanaachis; Keeper, Kiiwiichens, John, Sr., 1862-1951; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Little Grand Rapids, Alix trading post, [1930s]; A90
      "This is the Alix trading post. The highest building is the house--the other is the store. We had our tents in back of it." See also A89, A93, F73, F107
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Zhaabandowaan, Keeper family, [1930s]; A91
      p. 44 in Hallowell's Berens River Album, Zhaabandowaan, home of Kiiwiichens Keeper and his family. Two children in photo. [The Keeper dwelling Little Grand Rapids. Note stovepipe & the mixture of bark & canvas coverings. J. Brown 2/96] See also A89, A93, F73, F107.
      Keeper, Kiiwiichens, John, Sr., 1862-1951; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Keeper family, two women,a girl, a boy and two small children, [1930s] [1938?]; A92
      p. 45 in Hallowell Berens Album. Zhaabandowaan in Little Grand Rapids, Keeper family women and children. See also A89, A91, A93, A105, F73, F107.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kiwiichens Keeper, zhaabandowaan, [1930s]; A93
      p. 45 of Hallowell Berens River Album. Kiiwiichens Keeper (John Keeper Sr. - 1862-1951) ((also called Kiiwetapiihtank), brother of Alex Keeper and his zhaabandawaan (elongated tipi). A92 shows his wife and children at the opposite end of the dwelling.
      [Keeper dwelling? Little Grand Rapids? -- J. Brown 2/96]
      See also: A89, A91, A92, A105, F73, F107
      Keeper, Kiiwiichens, John, Sr., 1862-1951; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, pole structure, [1930s]; A94
      pole structure [smoke house - tepee? M. Matthews 4/12]
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, construction of waaginogaan, one, 1934; A95
      Waaginogaan construction, first step is to set poles in the ground. People, 1. Shoowap (wife of Ketigash Keeper, 2., 3., 4., 5. Ketigash Keeper.
      [Wáginogan framework] -- J. Brown
      See also: A96, A97, A98
      Keeper, Joe; Keeper, Ketigash; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, construction of waaginogaan, two., 1934; A96
      Construction of waaginogaan, Ketigash Keeper and boy tying poles together.
      See also: A95, A97, A98
      Keeper, Ketigash; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, construction of waaginogaan, three, [1934] [1938?]; A97
      Construction of waaginogaan, tying cross poles down. Ketigash Keeper and boy.
      [Wáginogan framework -- J. Brown 2/96]
      See also: A95, A96, A98
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, finished waaginogaan frame, with small boy, 1934; A98
      Waaginogaan framework complete. Small boy in front.
      See also: A95, A96, A97
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Shoowap Keeper, [1930s]; A99
      Shoowap Keeper, wife of Ketigash Keeper
      Keeper, Shoowap; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Little Grand Rapids man recovering canoe, note fire tower in distance., [1930s] [1936?]; A100
      Berens River white folks
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, family, [1930s]; A101
      p. 50 of Hallowell Berens River Album. Man, two women and four children in Little Grand Rapids.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids,"Jumps from cloud to cloud", [1930s]; A102
      p. 50 of Hallowell Berens River Album. "Jumps from Cloud to Cloud" - refers to lightning". [Aa'aazhawaana kwadaashiik - flies from cloud to cloud.- Pat Ningewance Dec 2012].
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Shoowap, [1930s] [1938?]; A103
      Shoowap, 2nd wife of Ketigash Keeper, with girl and baby in tikanagan. P. 51 of Hallowell Berens River Album.
      See also: A160, A161, A162
      Keeper, Shoowap; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Nenawan/Maggie Duck, [1930s]; A104
      Nenawan, [Nenaawin- Pat Ningewance Dec 2012]., Maggie Duck, Daughter of John Duck. Born 1917 and still alive in 1989 - [J Brown - 1996] P. 51 of Hallowell Berens River Album. See also: A102, F52
      Nenawan, Duck, (Maggie), ca.1917; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kiwiichens & Kamanaachis, [1930s]; A105
      p. 52 on Hallowell's Berens River Album. Kiiwchens and his wife Kamanaachis
      See also: A93
      Keeper, Kamanaachis; Keeper, Kiiwiichens, John, Sr., 1862-1951; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Maahtos?, [1930s]; A106
      p. 52 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. Maatos?
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, John James Keeper & wife Iskine and baby, [1930s] [1938?]; A107
      p. 53 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. John James Keeper and his wife, Iskine, and baby.
      Keeper, Iskine; Keeper, John James; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Noonaawas/Bella, [1930s] [1938?]; A108
      p. 53 in Hallowell's Berens River Album.
      See also: F162, A109
      Noonaawas; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Noonaawas/Bella, 1933; A109
      p. 54 of Hallowell's Berens River Album. [Bella? -- J. Brown 2/96]. See also A108, F162
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, girl, [1930s] [1938?]; A110